Miftahur Rizki

Kebumen, Central Java | +62 81229757228 | <u>linkedin.com/in/miftahurrrizki</u> miftahurrrizki@gmail.com

About Me

I am a Data Science student at Telkom University with a passion for technology, data, and design. With over three years of experience in various organizations, I have continuously upgraded my skills. I frequently use Python, SQL, and machine learning for data analysis. My capabilities extend beyond detailed data analysis and interpretation, as I am also adept at communicating my findings through engaging and easily comprehensible visual designs. I am always eager to learn new skills, a fast learner, and open to new challenges and opportunities to further improve my abilities.

Education

Bachelor of Data Science

Telkom University. GPA: 3.59/4.0 (6th Semester)

(2021 – Present)

Course related: Machine Learning, Cloud Computing, Database Management, Data Analytics, Statistics

Data Analytics and Software Development MSIB Kampus Merdeka Batch 6

RevoU Tech Academy. Grade: 98/100

(February 2024 – June 2024)

Course related: Data Analytics, Software Development

Experience

Badan Riset dan Inovasi Nasional Republik Indonesia (BRIN RI)

Data Scientist Researcher (Internship)

(July 2024 – September 2024)

- Research in Natural Language Processing (NLP)
- Developed Python programs for data collection from various sources
- Performed data annotation
- Developed a Named Entity Recognition (NER) Model
- Created visualization dashboards

Himpunan Mahasiswa Data Science Universitas Telkom

Mentor Data Visualization

(March 2024 – June 2024)

- Teaching data visualization course to fourth-semester students majoring in data science.
- Assisted students with completing major data visualization assignments.

Staff of Communication and Information

(May 2023 – January 2024)

- Crafted compelling Instagram content to convey organizational messages.
- Aligned design with identity for community impact.
- Designed Study Group Data Science materials.
- Created captivating booth designs for Student Fair events.

KAMI Foundation

Staff of Creative Media

(September 2023 – Desember 2023)

- Crafting Instagram content aligned with organizational missions and identity for community engagement.
- Designed promotional materials and visuals for organizational events.

OSIS SMAI Al-Azhar 9 Yogyakarta

Staff Kerohanian

August 2018 – September 2019)

- Developed and implemented religious work programs.
- Fostered religious education among members to deepen devotion.
- Coordinated activities for commemorating religious holidays.

Skills

Soft Skills:

- Analytical Skills
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Time Management
- Teamwork

Technical Skills:

- Programming Language: Python, SQL, Java, Javascript
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap
- Cloud Computing: Azure, Google Cloud
- Data Visualization: Tableau, Google Looker, Seaborn
- Data Mining
- Machine Learning: Linear Regression, Clustering, Classification, NLP, Forecasting
- Statistical Analysis
- Graphic Design: Figma, Adobe Illustrator
- Other Tools: BigQuery, RapidMiner, Jupyter Notebook, MySQL, Excel

Projects

Tweet Sentiment Analyzer

(May 2024 – June 2024)

Developed a web application to analyze tweet sentiments using machine learning (Bernoulli Naive Bayes and Logistic Regression). The project involved data collection, cleaning, and model building with Python. The API, built with FastAPI and Docker, was deployed to Azure. The frontend, created with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, was deployed via Vercel, displaying real-time analysis results

Dataisme

(January 2024 – Present)

"Dataisme" is a data science and visualization initiative, delivering accessible insights via Instagram and Medium. Utilizing Tableau and Figma, we craft engaging data narratives, making complex information visually captivating for all audiences. In this project, I was responsible for developing a comprehensive

content plan, conducting data research, designing visually appealing posts using Figma, and writing copy for both Instagram and Medium.

Jurnal Kuliner

(February 2023 – June 2023)

"Jurnal Kuliner" is a mobile app simplifying the search for top dining spots in Bandung, offering detailed information like menus, prices, locations, and reviews. With a focus on intuitive UI/UX design, the app ensures smooth navigation and clear information presentation for an engaging user experience.

The project documentation report can be viewed at **Project Report**.

The Richest (June 2023)

"The Richest" utilizes Tableau to visualize the impact of highest GDP values on global countries and associated influencing factors. This data analysis project offers insights crucial for economic planning, shedding light on the correlation between GDP and other indicators, contributing to informed policy decisions for global economic prosperity.

Other Projects

- Predicted customer churn for a telecommunications company and analyzed influencing factors (Data Science Week Competition by Telkom Indonesia)
- Predicted rainfall in the new capital city and analyzed influencing factors (Dataquest Competition by Universitas Airlangga).
- Predicted average vehicle speed on a road (RISTEK Datathon 2023 Competition by Universitas Indonesia).
- Created various data visualization dashboards using Tableau, Looker Studio and Streamlit.
- Developed a web application for tweet sentiment analysis using the Azure Ecosystem.
- Created various data visualization content on Instagram and wrote articles about data on Medium.
- View my design portfolio here: <u>Design Portfolio</u>

Achievements

• Top 4 Finalist in the National Infographic Competition 2024 – Dataquest (Data Science Competition by Universitas Airlangga).

Licenses & Certifications

Microsoft Power BI Data Analyst

Microsoft (April 2024)

Machine Learning for Beginner

Dicoding (January 2024)

Mastering Adobe Illustrator

Rubrik Grafis (August 2023)

Intermediate Python

DataCamp (July 2023)

Data Manipulation with Pandas

DataCamp (July 2023)

Dasar Visualisasi Data
Dicoding Indonesia (July 2022)

Dasar Pemrograman Web

Dicoding Indonesia (May 2021)